<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-04-03T23:56:07+00:00</updated><id>https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/</id><title type="html">Hydra Template</title><subtitle>Product marketing template for Jekyll.</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">The history of marketing</title><link href="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/marketing/2016/08/12/the-history-of-marketing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The history of marketing" /><published>2016-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/marketing/2016/08/12/the-history-of-marketing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/marketing/2016/08/12/the-history-of-marketing/">&lt;p&gt;The beginnings of digital marketing technology can be traced back to the 1980’s, when computers became sophisticated enough to store huge volumes of customer information. For a brief moment, no one knew what would happen in digital marketing, but by the 90’s it all became clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1146&quot; alt=&quot;Man&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of marketing is to a large extent a product of Internet’s history as markets have adapted to keep abreast of changes and keep up with the way the major Search Engines rank web pages. Major changes include, in chronological order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1991- Gopher: A network protocol, one of the very first query and search tools. Gopher was widely used for a couple of years, but usage has now fallen off, with barely 100 Gopher servers now indexed. 2. 1994- Launch of Yahoo, which was formerly known as “Jerry´s Guide to the World Wide Web” after one of its founders, Jerry Yang. Yahoo received in its first year over 1 million hits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;academic-studies&quot;&gt;Academic studies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study of the history of marketing as an academic field emerged only recently. Controversies and disputes abound in the field. The publication in 1976 of the book The History of Marketing Thought, by Robert Bartels marks a turning-point in marketing thought. Since then, academics specializing in marketing decided to imitate economics, distinguishing theory and practice. Two different fields of study emerged:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the history of marketing thought, giving theoretical accounts
marketing history, focusing on the history of marketing practice
This division parallels the distinction between the history of economic thought and economic history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1147&quot; alt=&quot;Thai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practitioners of the history of marketing thought note that both practitioners and academics know relatively little about the field.[citation needed] But history has significance for academics because it helps to define the baselines upon which they can recognize change and evolve marketing theory.On the other hand, proponents of marketing history argue that one cannot fully compare the marketing field with economics and hence suggest the impracticality of divorcing theory and practice. First, marketing scholars seldom engage in the practice of marketing as much as economists engage in the development and execution of public policies. Second, business people innovate in the marketing field, and the history of marketing will remain incomplete if one dissociates academia from practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1148&quot; alt=&quot;lavender flowers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following sections discuss both approaches to the history of marketing, closing with a debate about the standard chronology of marketing, a widely known hypothesis about the history of marketing, but one that historians in the marketing field have challenged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_marketing&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;: Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">The beginnings of digital marketing technology can be traced back to the 1980’s, when computers became sophisticated enough to store huge volumes of customer information. For a brief moment, no one knew what would happen in digital marketing, but by the 90’s it all became clear.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Definition of sales</title><link href="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/2016/08/06/definition-of-sales/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Definition of sales" /><published>2016-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/2016/08/06/definition-of-sales</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/2016/08/06/definition-of-sales/">&lt;p&gt;A person or organization expressing an interest in acquiring the offered item of value is referred to as a potential buyer, prospective customer or prospect. Buying and selling are understood to be two sides of the same “coin” or transaction. Both seller and buyer engage in a process of negotiation to consummate the exchange of values. The exchange, or selling, process has implied rules and identifiable stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1146&quot; alt=&quot;Cat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is implied that the selling process will proceed fairly and ethically so that the parties end up nearly equally rewarded. The stages of selling, and buying, involve getting acquainted, assessing each party’s need for the other’s item of value, and determining if the values to be exchanged are equivalent or nearly so, or, in buyer’s terms, “worth the price.” Sometimes, sellers have to use their own experiences when selling products with appropriate discounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;management-point-of-view&quot;&gt;Management point of view&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a management viewpoint it is thought of as a part of marketing, although the skills required are different. Sales often forms a separate grouping in a corporate structure, employing separate specialist operatives known as salespersons (singular: salesperson). Selling is considered by many to be a sort of persuading “art”. Contrary to popular belief, the methodological approach of selling refers to a systematic process of repetitive and measurable milestones, by which a salesman relates his or her offering of a product or service in return enabling the buyer to achieve their goal in an economic way. While the sales process refers to a systematic process of repetitive and measurable milestones, the definition of the selling is somewhat ambiguous due to the close nature of advertising, promotion, public relations, and direct marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1147&quot; alt=&quot;apricot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling is the profession-wide term, much like marketing defines a profession. Recently, attempts have been made to clearly understand who is in the sales profession, and who is not. There are many articles looking at marketing, advertising, promotions, and even public relations as ways to create a unique transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;common-terms&quot;&gt;Common terms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two common terms used to describe a salesperson are “Farmer” and “Hunter”. The reality is that most professional sales people have a little of both. A hunter is often associated with aggressive personalities who use aggressive sales technique. In terms of sales methodology a hunter refers to a person whose focus is on bringing in and closing deals. This process is called “sales capturing”. An example is a commodity sale such as a long distance sales person, shoe sales person and to a degree a car sales person. Their job is to find and convert buyers. A sales farmer is someone who creates sales demand by activities that directly influence and alter the buying process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1148&quot; alt=&quot;Marketing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;systems-approach&quot;&gt;Systems approach&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many believe that the focus of selling is on the human agents involved in the exchange between buyer and seller. Effective selling also requires a systems approach, at minimum involving roles that sell, enable selling, and develop sales capabilities. Selling also involves salespeople who possess a specific set of sales skills and the knowledge required to facilitate the exchange of value between buyers and sellers that is unique from marketing, advertising, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1149&quot; alt=&quot;Lady bugs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within these three tenets, the following definition of professional selling is offered by the American Society for Training and Development (ASTD):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The holistic business system required to effectively develop, manage, enable, and execute a mutually beneficial, interpersonal exchange of goods and/or services for equitable value.”
Team selling is one way to influence sales. Team selling is “a group of people representing the sales department and other functional areas in the firm, such as finance, production, and research and development”. (Spiro) Team selling came about in the 1990s through total quality management (TQM). TQM occurs when companies work to improve their customer satisfaction by constantly improving all of their operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sales&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;: Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">A person or organization expressing an interest in acquiring the offered item of value is referred to as a potential buyer, prospective customer or prospect. Buying and selling are understood to be two sides of the same “coin” or transaction. Both seller and buyer engage in a process of negotiation to consummate the exchange of values. The exchange, or selling, process has implied rules and identifiable stages.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sales effectiveness</title><link href="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/tips/2016/08/02/sales-effectiveness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sales effectiveness" /><published>2016-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/tips/2016/08/02/sales-effectiveness</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/tips/2016/08/02/sales-effectiveness/">&lt;p&gt;Sales effectiveness refers to the ability of a company’s sales professionals to “win” at each stage of the customer’s buying process, and ultimately earn the business on the right terms and in the right timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1146&quot; alt=&quot;American River&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-improve-sales-effectiveness&quot;&gt;How do you improve sales effectiveness?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improving sales effectiveness is not just a sales function issue; it’s a company issue, as it requires deep collaboration between sales and marketing to understand what’s working and not working, and continuous improvement of the knowledge, messages, skills, and strategies that sales people apply as they work sales opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales effectiveness has historically been used to describe a category of technologies and consulting services aimed at helping companies improve their sales results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies are creating sales effectiveness functions and have even given people titles such as VP of Sales Effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1147&quot; alt=&quot;Coins&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By analyzing sales force performance, managers can make changes to optimize sales going forward. Toward that end, there are many ways to gauge the performance of individual salespeople and of the sales force as a whole, in addition to total annual sales.” In a survey of nearly 200 senior marketing managers, 54 percent responded that they found the “sales force effectiveness” metric very useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sales_effectiveness&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;: Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Sales effectiveness refers to the ability of a company’s sales professionals to “win” at each stage of the customer’s buying process, and ultimately earn the business on the right terms and in the right timeframe.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Effective upselling techniques</title><link href="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/tips/2016/07/28/effective-upselling-techniques/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Effective upselling techniques" /><published>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/tips/2016/07/28/effective-upselling-techniques</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/tips/2016/07/28/effective-upselling-techniques/">&lt;p&gt;Upselling is a sales technique whereby a seller induces the customer to purchase more expensive items, upgrades or other add-ons in an attempt to make a more profitable sale. While it usually involves marketing more profitable services or products, it can be simply exposing the customer to other options that were perhaps not considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, large businesses usually combine upselling and cross-selling to maximize profit. In doing so, an organization must ensure that its relationship with the client is not disrupted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1146&quot; alt=&quot;Fair&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In restaurants and other similar settings, upselling is commonplace and an accepted form of business. In other businesses (e.g. car sales), the customer’s perception of the attempted upsell can be viewed negatively and impact the desired result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-you-upsell&quot;&gt;Why should you upsell?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upselling is a common practice for service providers that offer different service classes such as airlines (cf. Bohutinsky, 1990). According to “the journal of business and industrial marketing; written collaboratively by Michael J, Sheehan and Paul R, Prabhaker “It is five times more expensive to get a new customer as it is to hold onto a current one.” Selling to a new customer would mean having to start the sales process from the very beginning thus having to establish a new relationship with a different customer. This can be time consuming and often not very effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1147&quot; alt=&quot;Gleise&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-benefits&quot;&gt;The benefits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upselling to a customer that you have already built a rapport with, means that they are more likely to buy from you, listen to your suggestions and opinions and trust you. Selling to the same customer can lead to loyal customers and repeat sales. Upselling brings up the profit that the business makes and the value of the sale. However it is important to understand that although your main objective is to bring up revenue and increase the amount of the sale, a customers experience and their time with you influences future decisions that they make. An upsell can be beneficial to both the seller and the consumer if relevant products are being shown to the customer. For instance, if you had a strict budget of $20,000 for a car, you would not want to be sold a car for twice the amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Upselling&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;: Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Upselling is a sales technique whereby a seller induces the customer to purchase more expensive items, upgrades or other add-ons in an attempt to make a more profitable sale. While it usually involves marketing more profitable services or products, it can be simply exposing the customer to other options that were perhaps not considered.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The process for direct sales</title><link href="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/2016/07/20/the-process-for-direct-sales/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The process for direct sales" /><published>2016-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/2016/07/20/the-process-for-direct-sales</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://proud-alligator.cloudvent.net/sales/2016/07/20/the-process-for-direct-sales/">&lt;p&gt;Direct selling is the marketing and selling of products directly to consumers away from a fixed retail location. Peddling is the oldest form of direct selling. Modern direct selling includes sales made through the party plan, one-on-one demonstrations, and other personal contact arrangements as well as internet sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1145&quot; alt=&quot;Checkmate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;textbook-definition&quot;&gt;Textbook definition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A textbook definition is: “The direct personal presentation, demonstration, and sale of products and services to consumers, usually in their homes or at their jobs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-effective-is-direct-selling&quot;&gt;How effective is direct selling?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industry representative, the World Federation of Direct Selling Associations (WFDSA), reports that its 59 regional member associations accounted for more than US$183 billion in retail sales in 2014, through the activities of more than 62 million independent sales representatives. The United States Direct Selling Association (DSA) reported that in 2000, 55% of adult Americans had at some time purchased goods or services from a direct selling representative and 20% reported that they were currently(6%) or had been in the past(14%) a direct selling representative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1146&quot; alt=&quot;Office&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the WFDSA, consumers benefit from direct selling because of the convenience and service it provides, including personal demonstration and explanation of products, home delivery, and generous satisfaction guarantees. In contrast to franchising, the cost for an individual to start an independent direct selling business is typically very low with little or no required inventory or other cash commitments to begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most direct selling associations around the world require their members to abide by a code of conduct towards a fair partnership both with customers and salesmen…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most national direct selling associations are represented in the World Federation of Direct Selling Associations (WFDSA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hows-it-different-to-marketing&quot;&gt;How’s it different to marketing?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct selling is distinct from direct marketing because it is about individual sales agents reaching and dealing directly with clients. Direct marketing is about business organizations seeking a relationship with their customers without going through an agent/consultant or retail outlet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct selling consists of two main business models: single-level marketing, in which a direct seller makes money by buying products from a parent organization and selling them directly to customers, and multi-level marketing (also known as network marketing or person-to-person marketing), in which the direct seller makes money from both direct sales to customers and by sponsoring new direct sellers and earning a commission from their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1147&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberries&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Direct selling is the marketing and selling of products directly to consumers away from a fixed retail location. Peddling is the oldest form of direct selling. Modern direct selling includes sales made through the party plan, one-on-one demonstrations, and other personal contact arrangements as well as internet sales.</summary></entry></feed>